Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 14 -- Materials held at the University of Pennsylvania 1705-1788 Mss.B.F85inventory14
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence (University of Pennsylvania), 1758-1788
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 24; A.L.S. 2p.; Bouget, A. Morat
    Lost all his fortune in a Colonial indigo plantation; applies for assistance.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 24; A.L.S. 2p.; Genet, [Edme Jacques]
    Has made extracts for his paper and has then sent the letters to Comte de Vergennes.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 24; A.L.S. 1p.; Missa, -----. Paris
    Inviting him and his grandson to dinner.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 25; A.L.S. 2p.; de Peyrelongue, Madame Dauber. Marmande
    Begging him to secure the release of her son who is held a prisoner by the British at St. Augustine.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 25; A.L.S. 1p.; Hartmann, Rudolphe Ernest. Amsterdam
    Distressing situation of himself and family; begs him to secure the payment of the debt mentioned in a former letter.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 26; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Bristow, Benjamin. Paris
    Asking for the address of Mr. Samuel Adams.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 27; A.L.S. 1p.; Le Roux, C.J. Paris
    Requesting his presence at a meeting of the College of Bayeux; will read a poem, addressed to the King, on the hostilities of the English.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 June 28; A.L.S. 1p.; de la Varenne, Pierre Jean Etienne Mauduit
    Announcing a postponement of the public meeting of the Royal Society of Medicine.
  - Appendix, 1778 June 29; A.L.S. 1p.; Gébelin, Antoine Court de. Paris
    Inviting him and his family to be guests of honor at a banquet to be given at Passy by La Loge des Neuf Soeurs.
  - Appendix, 1778 July 1; A.L.S. 1p.; Junker, George Adam. Paris
    Desires to communicate something concerning the United States.
  - Appendix, 1778 July 2; A.L.S. 2p.; La Blancherie, Claude-Mammès de Pahin Champlain de
    Feels assured that the establishment for which he solicits aid will be success, and that its income will always exceed its expenses.
  - Appendix, 1778 July 2; A.L.S. 1p.; Richard, -----. Paris
    Asking for news of M. Lebon.
  - Appendix, [1778.] July 3; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; de Ruthiere, Claude Caeloman
    Reasons why he desires the immediate return of his History of Anarchy in Poland.
  - Appendix, [1778.] July 4 Saturday; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; de Ruthiere, Claude Caeloman
    Desiring the return of his Mss., History of Anarchy, sent for Dr. Franklin's inspection.
  - Appendix, 1778 July 4; A.L.S. 1p.; De Bout, -----. Paris
    Desiring the return of a letter from the Chevalier de Bazantin, together with one from the Comtesse de Lameth.
  - Appendix, 1778 July 5; A.L.S. 3p.; Gauthier, Marc Fran"çois. Brest
    Accused of passing counterfeit money and sentenced to the galleys for life; declares his innocence; begs Dr. Franklin to procure his release and allow him to enter the United States navy.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1778.] July 10; A.L.S. 4p.; Genet, [Edme Jacques]
    News from America; rumors of the evacuation of Philadelphia; announcement in the Courier de l'Europe of a Committee appointed by Congress to treat with the English for peace; desires authority to stigmatize this report as a lie.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 July 12; A.L.S. 1p.; De Bout, -----. Paris
    Returning the Chevalier de Bazantin's letter; forward Dr. Franklin's letter to Madame de Broglie, Comtesse de Lameth.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 July 12; A.L.S. 2p.; Marcenay, Madame Herbaut de
    Expressing Mme. de Breget's acknowledgments and her regret at being unable to accept his invitiation to dinner.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 July 14; A.L.S. 2p.; Martin, -----. Dunkirk
    Desiring news of his son who left Nantes on March 12th for America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 July 15; A.L.S. Le Fort. 2p.; M. Faure, Donneau and Co. Marseilles
    Desiring to know the truth of the report of the capture of the "Elégante" by the English ship "Emerald," and the decision of the Congress of Williamsburg to repay Capt. Collineau of the "Elégante," owing to treachery having been used in the capture.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 July 18; A.L.S. 1p.; d'Hanache, Marquis Alexandre. Paris
    Expressing a desire for a personal meeting; sent letters to be forwarded to his relative, Count Sterling [William Alexander, Earl of Stirling]; thinks by this time the answers should have arrived.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 July 28; A.L.S. 2p.; Plombard and Legris. Nantes
    Sends a bill of Henry Laurens for acceptance; M. Plombard going to America on business; offers his services.
  - Appendix, 1778 August 3; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; de Conwaiy, Comte
    Wishes to call on Dr. Franklin and Mr. [John] Adams and present M. de Brion and the Chevalier Alexandre d'Hanache; M. de Brion about to start for San Domingo.
  - Appendix, 1778 August 5; A.L.S. 2p.; La Blancherie, Claude-Mammès de Pahin Champlain de
    Urging his presence at an approaching meeting of that establishment which he has so generously patronized.
  - Appendix, 1778 August 17; A.L.S. 1p.; La Blancherie, Claude-Mammès de Pahin Champlain de
    Inviting him to a meeting on the following day.
  - Appendix, 1778 August 23; A.L.S. 3p.; Henry, -----. Madrid
    Ardent desire to enter the American service as engineer; account of his previous work; begs Dr. Franklin to help him.
    A. E. by Dr. Franklin. "The Commissioners have no orders to send more engineers; when they have, his application will be considered."
  - Appendix, 1778 August 24; A.L.S. 1p.; Droüet, -----. Paris
    Desires an interview.
  - Appendix, 1778 August 28; A.L.S. 3p.; Desnos, Odolant. Alençon
    His only son has disappeared with the money given him to take his degree in medicine at the University of Paris; has probably assumed a false name; begs Dr. Franklin to find him.
  - Appendix, 1778 August 30; A.L.S. 2p.; De La Faye, -----. Paris
    Requesting an answer to M. Ponteney's proposal to furnish supplies for America.
    A.E. by Dr. Franklin. Orders for America all filled; recommends M. Pontency to correspond with Mr. [Jonathan] Williams, [Jr.], at Nantes.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 September 21; A.L.S. 3p.; Duplacy, Joseph Ruault. Saint Brieuc
    Has had thirteen years' experience on board British vessels; wishes to secure a position on one of the ships at Nantes. (In French.)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 October 2; L.S. 2p.; L. Laffitte, Laurens and François Mongin and Jacques Fraissignea. Alresford, Hampshire
    Captured at sea in October, 1777; endured cruel treatment in a British prison until released on parole; desire to be exchanged.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 October 23; A.L.S. 1p.; Hopkins, Daniel. Boston
    Begging his influence to secure the release of the writer's brother-in-law, John Palmer, who has been a prisoner in England for eighteen months.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 December 4; A.L.S. 1p.; Genet, [Edme Jacques]
    The King of England's speech, with an abstract of the debates in both Houses, will appear on the morrow; has treated the lie about Gen. Washington as it deserved.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1778 December 21; A.L.S. W[illia]m Vernon, Pres[iden]t, J[ohn] Deshon. 3p.; The Navy Board, Eastern Department. Boston
    Orders for Capt. [Pierre] Landais, of the "Alliance," relative to his passenger, the Marquis de la Fayette; instructions covering his movements during the voyage to France and upon his arrival there.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, A.L.S. 1p.; Deinet, -----. Frankfort-on-Main
    Sends a book of which other copies may be ordered, if so desired.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, A.L.S. 1p.; La Plaigne, Emmanuel-Pierre de
    Introducing Messrs. [Charles] Armand and de Guäy, two Captains of artillery whom he has enlisted in the service of Georgia; well pleased with his recruits.
  - Appendix, 1778; L. in 3d P. 2p.; Dubois, Jean Baptiste
    His service in the French army; desires to be a Second Lieutenant in the United States army.
  - Appendix, 1778; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Grand, Ferdinand
    Concerning Dr. Franklin's indebtedness for books and for a sum sent to Mr. W[illia]m Hodgson on behalf of the American prisoners.
  - Appendix, 1778; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Keay, -----. Paris
    Enclosing an account of an accident in Philadelphia; the lightning-rods upon the house were certainly put up subsequent to the accident.
  - Appendix, 1778; A.L.S. 1p.; Wildrik, W. Namur
    Begging him once again to reply to his letters.
  - Appendix, 1779 January 24; A.L.S. 1p.; Lee, Arthur. Chaillot
    M. [Ferdinand] Grand probably has the public papers he desires. Encloses Mr. [Silas] Deane's remarks.
  - Appendix, 1779 January 31; A.L.S. 2p.; Digges, B. B----d Thomas
    Hails with delight the disputes and discussions in America; opportunity to accelerate the subjugation of the revolted Colonies. Sorry to report successes by the French privateers. Sketches Lord Shelburne's future policy with respect to America; his own ability to aid him. Concerning the offers made by the Administration [in England] to purchase French neutrality in the present contest.
  - Appendix, 1779 February 2; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Mrs. Gibbes and Miss Stevens. Calais
    Prevented from paying their respects by the indisposition of Mrs. Gibbes; compliments to Mr. [John] Adams.
  - Appendix, 1779 February 2; L.S. 3p.; Stephen Hills and five other officers of the "Alliance."
    Desiring to be furnished with clothing and money; their monthly pay wholly inadequate.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 February 7; A.L.S. 3p.; Digges, Thomas. Bristol
    News from England; a fleet ready to sail from the West Indies. A regiment to be sent to Quebec to keep patriotic Canadians quiet. The British Ministry steering between peace and war; rumored changes in the Ministry. Stocks affected by reports of disunion in America; Americans expected to propose terms short of independence. No indication that [Arthur] Lee now has improper communications with Lord Shelburne. Exorbitant prices in America; suggestions for relief.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 February 7; A.L.S. 1p.; Deane, Silas. Philadelphia
    Introducing Major Montford, who served with destinction in America under Count Pulaski.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 February 7; L.S. 1p.; Stephen Hills and six other Officers of the "Alliance." Brest
    Desiring the money promised them for their necessary expenses when they should reach France.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 February 8; A.L.S. 1p.; Landais, Capt. Pierre
    Asking that the French authorities may have everything ready in the harbor for repairing the ship.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 February 10; A.L.S.; Johns, Aquila. On board the "Buckskin."
    Certifying to his capture of the English privateer "Spy"; gives the parole of the "Spy's" officers and crew.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 February 27; A.L.S. 2p.; Blodget, Nathan. Purser of the "Alliance." Brest
    A list of articles ordered for transportation to America on board the "Alliance."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 March 2; A.L. 2p.; Grand, Ferdinand
    The return of bills from Congress would be more of a blow to the United States than the loss of Georgia. Question of the American Commissioners being allowed to draw upon French banks.
  - Appendix, 1779 March 3; L.S. 2p.; Benjamin Pierce and twelve other Petty Officers of the "Alliance." Brest
    Complaining that Capt. [Pierre] Landais has not paid them their wages and has not furnished sufficient provisions; the petitioners in great need of clothing.
  - Appendix, 1779 March 26; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Lee, Arthur. Paris
    Enclosing an account of Mr. [John D.] Schweighauser, which he has found among his papers.
  - Appendix, 1779 March 29; L.S. 1p.; Faynard, Jacques. Paris
    Has invented a powder for stopping hemorrhages both internal and external; invites him to be present at a trial of it, to be made before some members of the Academy of Surgery.
  - Appendix, 1779 April 7; A.L.S. 1p.; Tillet, Mathieu. Paris
    Invitation to dine with M. Amelot, President of the Académie des Sciences, on the day of the public meeting when Dr. Franklin will read one of the papers.
  - Appendix, 1779 April 8; A.L.S. 3p.; Boule, -----. Paris
    Has taken money with which he was entrusted; begs Dr. Franklin to keep this confession secret; promises to repay the money in six months and to show his repentence by his future conduct.
  - Appendix, 1779 April 17; A.L.S. 2p.; Kéralio, Agathon Guynement, chevalier de
    Inviting him and his grandson to dinner on the 22d.
  - Appendix, 1779 April 29; A.L.S. 3p.; Lovell, James. Philadelphia
    Hopes that he has received his appointment as Minister Plenipotentiary to France. [Silas] Deane's recall necessary. Arthur Lee's destruction determined upon by a party in America. Urges him to write frequently to Congress in order to show that there is more than one man [Deane] in the universe who can please the Court of France. In the bitter discussions in America, Franklin has not escaped censure.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 May 18; A.L.S. 1p.; Digges, V.I.D. ----- d Thomas
    Gen, [Sir William] Howe's evidence yet before the House; likelihood of the Ministry abandoning the idea of America's subjugation.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 June 1; A.L. 1p.; Vergennes, Charles Gravier, comte de. Versailles
    Questions which must be answered before a passport can be issued for Messrs. [Sir William] Jones and [John] Paradise.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 June 8; L.S. 2p.; Stephen Hills and Joseph Adams. On board the "Alliance," L'Orient
    Capt. John Paul Jones has tried in vain to influence [Capt. Pierre] Landais to do right; obliged to resign their position as officers, owing to the manner in which Capt. Landais governs the ship.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 June ?; L.S. John Jay, Presid[en]t 2p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Enclosing Acts of Congress of June 5th and 10th by which Dr. Franklin is directed to pay certain sums to M. [Pierre Augustin Caron de] Beaumarchais for supplies purchased and sent to America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 July 8; L.S. 3p.; Vesey, Peter et al., Boling
    Released from an English prison, only to be recaptured and imprisoned by the French; beg to be sent home to their families in America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 June 13, July 9, 16; A.L.S. James Lovell. 4p.; The Continental Congress, Committee of Foreign Affairs. Philadelphia
    Resolution of Congress, calling upon the Commissioners for information of their proceedings with M. [Pierre Augustin Caron de] Beaumarchais; sends journals and gazettes. Query whether no American privateer will retaliate on the coast of England for outrages committed by Great Britain on the American coast. Gen. [Benjamin] Lincoln's militia did well in the attack on [Gen. Augustine] Prevost.
    (In quadruplicte.)
  - Appendix, 1779 July 21; L.S. Fra[ncis] Lewis. 2p.; The Continental Congress, Commercial Committee. Philadelphia
    Requesting Dr. Franklin not to permit bills from Oliver Pollock, Continental Agent at New Orleans to be protested.
  - Appendix, 1779 August 6, September 16; A.L.S. 4p.; Lovell, James. Philadelphia
    Complains of the few letters received from him. [Silas] Deane's publication of December 5th, full of lies; believes he has ruined his chance of public usefulness. No longer any distinction in America between the Ministry and the people of England; from King to soot-boy they wish to say "Oak Colonies."
    (In triplicate.)
  - Appendix, 1779 September 28; A.L.S. Cha[rle]s Thomson, Sec[retar]y. 1p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Announcing the election of Samuel Huntington as President of Congress.
  - Appendix, 1779 August 6, September 29; L.S. Cha[rle]s Thomson, Sec[retar]y. 1p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Resolutions relative to the [American] Commissioners' Accounts.
    Printed in Journals of Congress, Philadelphia, 1782, V, 308, 309, 373.
  - Appendix, 1779 October 26; D.S. 1p.; ----- Vines and other Officers of the "Vengeance." On board the "Vengeance."
    Certifying to Capt. [Pierre] Landais's refusal to obey orders.
    (In French. Copy.)
  - Appendix, 1779 October 28; D.S. 2p.; Ricot, Philippe Nicolas. Texel
    Certifying to insubordination on the part of Capt. [Pierre] Landais on several specified occasions.
  - Appendix, 1779 October 30; D.S. 7p.; The Officers of the American Squadron. Texel
    Testimony of officers on the "Alliance," "Pallas" and "Bon Homme Richard," supporting the charges made by [John Paul] Jones against [Pierre] Landais.
    (Copy.)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 November 2; L.S. 2p.; Henry Laurence and Others. Mill Prison, Plymouth
    Complain of having been cruelly confined for over two years; appeal to him for relief.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 November 10; L.S. 1p.; ----- Ladixmerie and other Officers of the Loge des Neuf Soeurs. Paris
    Urging him to be present at their public fête; nothing else could give the meeting such éclat.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 November 15; A.L.S. 1p.; Digges, Thomas. London
    Introducing M. Fabroni and M. Fontana, two learned young Italian travellers.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 November 15; Mem. 2p.; la Hune, -----. Passy
    Tailor's bill receipted.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 November 24; L.S. 4p.; de Kloguene, Denis-Nicolas Cottineau
    Complaining of the conditions on board the "Serapis"; equipments, food and irons for the prisoners lacking; the ship unseaworthy.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1779 December 3; A.L.S. 3p.; Digges, Donald Forbes Thomas. Stepney
    Moneys paid out for Dr. Franklin; cool attitude of Messrs. [John] J[ay] and [Arthur] L[ee]. American news in England; position of the British troops. Less talk of vigorously prosecuting the American war, in spite of Lord North's speech; report that "through the wicked machinations of Dr. Franklin, a very good understanding exists between Ireland and the Rebel Congress."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, [1779.]; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Arendt, Baron d'
    Wishes to be paid the 25 louis d'or promised him by Mr. William Lee, as per enclosed letter [Copy, 1p.] for purchasing supplies; has overstaid his furlough from his regiment in Virginia, in order to discharge this commission; begs Dr. Franklin to give him a line explaining the delay.
  - Appendix, [1778-1779.]; A.N. 1p.; Chaumont, Jacques-Donatien Le Ray de
    A statement of the receipts and expenditures on account of the United States in France.
  - Appendix, 1779; A.L.S. 1p.; ----- Chaumont, Secretaire General des Hussards
    Sends a petition from a German Prince, who wishes his name withheld until an answer is received.
  - Appendix, 1780 January 1; A.L.S. 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Description of the hats, shoes and hose to be purchased for Congress; desires to know what the uniform is to be.
  - Appendix, 1780 January 4; A.L.S. Sam[uel] Huntington, President. 1p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Directing him to apply to the French Court for aid in securing the exchange of Henry Laurens. Similar directions sent to John Jay.
  - Appendix, 1780 January 5; D.S. Ringuin, Griffin. 3p.; The Admiralty Court of France. Morlaix
    Official report of the character and cargo of the prize "James and Thomas" taken by the American ship, "Black Prince" and brought to Morlaix.
  - Appendix, 1780 January 5; D.S. Ringuin and others. 2p.; The Admiralty Court of France. Morlaix
    Testimony of François Fick concerning the capture of the prize "James and Thomas" by the "Black Prince"; [extract from the reports.]
  - Appendix, 1780 January 10; A.L.S. 3p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Desiring information about the clothing for 15,000 men, which he is getting ready in accordance with the paln of Dr. Franklin and M. de Chaumont.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 January 11, 12; A.D.S. Le Ridelle. 4p.; The Admiralty Court of France. Morlaix
    Official report of invoicing and sealing the cargo of the British prize, "Camden," taken by the American ship, "Black Princess." [Extract from the minutes.]
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 January 13; A.D.S. Le Ridelle. 3p.; The Admiralty Court of France. Morlaix
    Testimony of Robert Storey concerning the capture of the English vessel, "Camden," by the "Black Princess." [Extract from the Court Record.]
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 January 13; A.D.S. Le Ridelle. 3p.; The Admiralty Court of France. Morlaix
    Testimony of Thomas Borch, a British prisoner, concerning the capture of the "Camden" by the "Black Princess." [Extract from the Minutes.]
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 January 13; D.S. Le Ridelle. 4p.; The Admiralty Court of France. Morlaix
    Testimony of Abraham Needam concerning the capture of the "Camden" by the "Black Princess."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 January 18; D.S. Le Bitter, Interpreter. 3p.; The Admiralty Court of France. Morlaix
    Concerning a protection from imprisonment of nine men and one cabin boy on board the "Camden."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 January 19; D.S. Ringuin, Griffin. 3p.; The Admiralty Court of France. Morlaix
    Testimony of John Hunt concerning the prize "James and Thomas" taken by the "Black Prince." [Extract from the Minutes.]
  - Appendix, 1780 January 21; A.L.S. 1p.; Ringuin, -----. Morlaix
    Sends the testimony concerning the capture of the "James and Thomas" by the "Black Prince."
  - Appendix, 1780 January 27; A.L.S. 1p.; Chaumont, -----. Paris
    Concerning the proposal of a German Prince to furnish a regiment of soldiers for the American service.
  - Appendix, 1780 February 1; A.L.S. 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Enclosing a letter from Capt. [John] Manley, now in Mill Prison. Has drawn on M. [Le Ray] de Chaumont for money.
  - Appendix, 1780 February 2; A.L.S. 1p.; Ringuin, -----. Morlaix
    Sends the testimong concerning the capture of the English ship, "Comden," by the "Black Princess."
  - Appendix, 1780 February 19; A.L.S. 4p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Business of shipping goods to America; orders of Congress concerning the clothing, conflict with the orders given by [Marquis de] la Fayette.
  - Appendix, 1780 February 26; A.L.S. 1p.; Williams, John
    Indignantly denies that he was in Communication with the British Government, while in England; wishes to go to America and share that fate of his countrymen.
  - Appendix, 1780 February 26; A.L.S. 4p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Begs Dr. Franklin to deny the report that his Uncle [John Williams] was in communication with the British Government while in London. Reported capture of six British transports bound from New York, with provisions for the gurison at Penobscot.
  - Appendix, 1780 February 29; A.L.S. 3p.; Materre, ------
    Requesting news of Jacques Materre who sailed from Bordeaux on March 22, 1777, for the United States in order to enter the army.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 March 5; A.L.S. 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Introducing Mr. [George] Mason, [Jr.], of Virginia.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 March 7; A.L.S. 3p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Concerning the shipment of clothing to Rochelle. Requests a passage to America for his Uncle [John Williams] and for Mr. [Joseph] Gridley, whose health requires his return. Asks for the receipt for Crown Soap.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 March 19; A.D.S. 2p.; Alexander, William. Paris
    Certifying to being present at a conversation between Mr. [William] Pult[e]ney and Dr. Franklin, when the former made proposals for a reconciliation with America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 March 25; A.L.S. 3p.; Rousseau, Jean. Geneva
    Writes on behalf of a person who wishes employment as Secretary.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 March 27; A.L.S. 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Concerning the terms agreed upon with M. [Le Ray] de Chaumont for shipping freight to America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1780 March 30; A.L.S. 3p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.